# BLAKELY BURNS SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## CONTACT

## **SKILLS**

# SUMMARY

JavaScript, Node.js, Python, Flask, React, Express, SQL, PostgreSQL, HTML/CSS, Redux, Jest, Docker, Git, CI/CD, CircleCl, Cypress, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Communication, Collaboration

Software developer and former science teacher with five years of experience in education dedicated to helping students investigate real-world problems and design creative solutions. Now applying that same passion to solving problems through code. Experienced in building full-stack applications with Javascript, React, Node, Express, Python, and SQL. Looking for a position where I can make a meaningful contribution, collaborate with other developers, and grow my skills.

## **PROJECTS**

#### **TEACHER LAB**

A web app for teachers designed to make backward planning and collaboration more efficient. API developed with Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL, using JWTs for authentication.

#### DIVE ATI AS

A web app that helps scuba divers discover new dive sites, share their experiences and keep a record of past dives. Full-stack app developed with Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, and JavaScript

#### JOBI Y

 $\ensuremath{\mathsf{A}}\xspace$  job search web app where users can find job postings and look up company information.

Full-stack app developed with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React, and Redux

#### **LANGCHAT**

A web-based chat app that helps users learn a new language by allowing them to chat with other users who speak their target language. Full-stack app developed with Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, and Socket.io

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **SPRINGBOARD**

Software Engineering Career Track - Student

Aug. 2020 to June 2021

700+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in frontend web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.

## **SWING EDUCATION**

Substitute Teacher

Ventura, Ca Sept. 2019 to Apr. 2020

Led classes of 20-40 students across a wide range of grades and subjects

Supported students with a variety of skills and backgrounds

Implemented lesson plans and worked with students to reinforce concepts and skills introduced by the teacher

### SANTA PAULA UNIFIED SCHOOL DISTRICT

Science Teacher

Santa Paula, Ca Aug. 2018 to June 2019

Developed and implemented engaging inquiry-based lesson plans

Collaborated with teachers and administrators to develop, evaluate, and revise science curriculum

Analyzed assessment data and adjusted lesson plans and teaching strategies to improve student outcomes

#### PANYADEE, THE BRITISH INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL OF SAMUI

Science/Math Teacher

Koh Samui, Thailand Aug. 2013 to July 2016

Engaged students in learning science and math through inquiry, discussion, and project based learning Supported students from various linguistic backgrounds in developing their English language skills

## **EDUCATION**

## **Springboard**

Certification Software Engineering Career Track 2021

9-month intensive course in Software Engineering methodologies and technologies

#### **Western Governors University**

Master of Arts Teaching Science 2018

## **Gordon College**

Bachelor of Science Biology 2009